https://www.met.ie/housing-gov-ie-privacy-policy

Data Protection
Under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), in force from 25th May 2018, organisations are required to meet a very high standard in how they collect, use and protect personal data.
Personal Data
Personal data is any information that can identify an individual person. This includes a name, an ID number, location data (for example, location data collected by a mobile phone) or a postal address, online browsing history, images or anything relating to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of a person.
Processing
Processing refers to any operation or set of operations performed on personal data. Processing includes storing, collecting, retrieving, using, combining, erasing and destroying personal data, and can involve automated or manual operations.
Data Controller
A data controller refers to a person, company, or other body which determines the purposes and means of processing of personal data.
As a data controller, the Department of Housing, Local Government and Heritage must ensure that when it processes personal data it does so in accordance with the data protection principles set out in the GDPR, as follows:
processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent manner in relation to individuals;
collected for specified, explicit and legitimate purposes and not further processed in a manner that is incompatible with those purposes; further processing for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes shall not be considered to be incompatible with the initial purposes;
adequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary in relation to the purposes for which they are processed;
accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date; every reasonable step must be taken to ensure that personal data that are inaccurate, having regard to the purposes for which they are processed, are erased or rectified without delay;
kept in a form which permits identification of data subjects for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the personal data are processed; personal data may be stored for longer periods insofar as the personal data will be processed solely for archiving purposes in the public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or statistical purposes subject to implementation of the appropriate technical and organisational measures required by the GDPR in order to safeguard the rights and freedoms of individuals; and
processed in a manner that ensures appropriate security of the personal data, including protection against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage, using appropriate technical or organisational measures.
Privacy Statement
The Department of Housing, Local Government and Heritage is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This privacy statement explains how the Department processes the personal data provided to it, and what rights you may exercise in relation to your personal data.
Data Protection Policy
This Data Protection Policy sets out the Department’s commitment to protecting the rights and privacy of individuals and details how we will ensure compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and Irish data protection legislation.
Subject Access Requests
You have the right to obtain from the Department of Housing, Local Government and Heritage confirmation as to whether or not your personal data is being processed. You also have the right to obtain a copy of the personal data undergoing processing, as well certain information about the processing.
How to make a Subject Access Request
Contacting Us
If you require further information, please contact the Department’s Data Protection Officer, details below:
Data Protection Officer,
Department of Housing, Local Government and Heritage,
Newtown Road,
Copyright © 2016 Department of Housing, Local Government and Heritage
Web Design and Development by Annertech
